The person I have a crush on is distancing herself from me.
I'd like to ask a question about dating and relationships.
It's not much of a relationship since it is a crush from my part only.
I graduated from all-boys middle school and high school.
Then I met a girl at a freshman club in my university and took a liking to her.
I got to know her more and found out that she had a boyfriend.
Once we became friends, I asked her casually, and she said she had a boyfriend.
But then they broke up a week ago.
And?
But I can't just be happy about it.
Before she broke up, I'd been acting really nice to her on the class trips.
She probably noticed that I like her.
Since the breakup last week, she has been distancing herself.
We didn't talk about it, but I could feel it.
It seems like she wants some space.
Do you know the reason?
Because she knows that I like her.
She knows that you like her, so she feels pressured?
Yes, I think so. What should I do now?
Don't put any pressure on her then.
How do I not burden her?
You can simply ask her, "I like you, but does that make you feel uncomfortable?"
You don't need permission to like someone.
You can simply like her.
If she feels burdened about your feelings for her, it could be that she's still heartbroken from her ex-boyfriend leaving her.
When a man leaves a woman, she can either fall for another guy soon after,
or be on guard thinking that the next guy might be the same.
I am saying that there is more than one side.
If she's the one who left, she did because she disliked that person.
So she might not be ready for another guy to like her.
Do you understand?
Yes.
And we don't know what happened.
Even if you know who broke up with whom, you can't tell how she feels about it.
So you can't tell whether she is burdened by your feelings or she is comforted but needs some space.
I see two options.
One is to act just as before since you can't tell how she feels.
Don't get swayed by whether she feels burdened or likes you, but just follow your own pace.
Simply ask, "I like you, but does that make you feel burdened?"
If she says, "Yes, you are a bit too close," then you can give her more space.
If she says it's fine, then act as before.
It's faster to ask than worrying about it.
Then, of those two options, are you recommending me to ask her directly?
I don't wish to interfere in your life. Why?
If I interfere, you'll want me to take the responsibility.
You will ask me to share the responsibility.
Living alone is hard enough, and you want me to take the responsibility of your lives.
You choose which option to follow.
You can choose both as well.
You can try one. If that doesn't work out, try the other.
Okay, thank you.